Richard Lummus

206.384.0550

Seattle, Wa 98107 ◆

♦ <u>richard.c.lummus90@gmail.com</u>

https://github.com/apocpax → https://www.linkedin.com/in/richardlummus/

Software Engineer

1+ year of coding training combine with over 10 years of customer focus experience

Hard-working and ready to learn software engineer. Using past detail-oriented experience as well as my drive to expand my knowledge to deliver results. Track record of constant self improvement and ability to work well in a team or by myself to insure the greatest outcome. Never letting obscules get in my way or stop me from reaching the goals I strive for.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

HTML | CSS | MERN Full Stack | React | Javascript | Jquery Customer Service | Team Leadership | Scheduling | Problem Solving |

CAREER EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

Coding Projects

During and after my software engineer bootcamp I dove into coding projects. I used these projects to add many different skills to help make me a more well rounded software engineer

- Personal Profile website,
- Social Media Website, including photo hosting as well as live chat feature.
- Ecommerce Website with Paypal API payment attached as well as add different stock features.
- taking feedback from live testers to improve websites.

Lowe's, Bellevue, WA 2011 – 2018

Cashier to customer Service Department Manager

Started from the bottom position as a cashier but through my drive and hard work I was promoted 6 times in 7 years to the position of Customer Service Department Manager. In this position i had a lot of responsibility some of which were

- Team leader for over 30 people.
- In charge of starting and Training for Lowes.com online orders at the store level.
- Taking care of all email complaints from customers and problems solving a fix to the situation.
- Helping other departments in high pressure situations to find the best possible outcome with time restraints.
- developing associates to grow into higher positions.

Safeway, Seattle, Wa 2011 - present

Night Crew

Several months after finishing my bootcamp my blind grandfather got sick as I was the only one in my family that had the ability and time to take care of him, I put finding an engineer job on hold to help him into his passing.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Software Engineer program | General Assembly Bootcamp